[Music playing]
In the not too distant future, somewhere in time and space,
Mike Nelson and his robot pals are caught in an endless chase.
Pursued by a woman whose name is Pearl,
an evil gal who wants to rule the world.
She threw a few things in her purse.
And in her rocket ship, she hunts him
all across the universe.
I'll get you!
I'll send him cheesy movies, the worst I can find.
He'll have to sit and watch them all, and I'll monitor his mind.
Now keep in mind Mike can't control
where the movies begin or end.
He'll try to keep his sanity with the help
of his robot friends.
Robot.
Come on, you're on.
Don't servo.
Check me out.
I am--
If you're wondering how he eats and breathes
and other science facts, just repeat to yourself,
it's just a show.
You should really just relax.
Oh, Mystery Science Theater 3000.
Oh, Mom.
Hey, what gives?
I'm not done yet.
I don't want to go.
[Splat]
[Laughter]
Oh, that Warren Christopher.
He's a hoot.
Funny, funny man.
Crow.
I'll be with you in a moment.
Guy kills me.
Have you been helped?
Oh, it's me, Tom.
Tom Servo.
Tom?
Tom Servo?
Oh, gosh, it's great to see you.
Gypsy.
Gypsy, I missed you.
I missed you too, Crow.
And you are?
Crow, it's me, Mike.
Oh, mine's Crow.
I don't believe we've met.
Of course we have.
We spent years together watching bad movies.
Uh-huh.
If your little friend need to lie down--
I don't think he needs--
Crow, someone or something pulled us back here.
We need to find out who or why.
Well, anything I can do to help, Gary.
It's Mike.
Like it matters to him.
This guy is gone.
[Blubbering]
Mike, I think it's important we know where we are
and whether or not we have control of the ship.
Right, that's a good point.
Which, by the way, looks terrific.
What did you do to it, Crow?
Well, I was only at the edge of the universe
for about five minutes.
I got all bored and stuff.
So I came back here, had a few hundred years to kick around.
I did all the decorating myself, though I worked with a consultant
on some of the--
Crow, Crow, Crow, Crow, where are we?
I don't know.
Do we have control of the ship?
Uh, no.
Mike, we're about to crash straight
into the surface of an unidentified class M planet.
Oh, no.
Well, you could pull that emergency brake cord right up there.
What if we get--
[screaming]
But don't do that because you dropped the tranny right out of the middle.
Well, nobody asked you to come back here.
Great.
Gypsy, status report.
Ship's engine's badly damaged.
Hull integrity's sound.
Currently in orbit over a class M planet.
Gypsy, what planet?
Unknown, though it does appear to have a nice Asia.
Oh, and a North America and a very nice Africa.
That's Earth.
We're back to Earth, folks.
[Cheering]
Yes, yes, but what year?
Uh, time indicator's not functional, Mike.
Ok.
Contact planet put up on monitor one.
[Beeping]
Lab?
[Screaming]
We'll be right back.
[Music playing]
[Screaming]
Look, I don't know how the--
[screaming]
How did you get the word?
[Screaming]
How would you--
It speaks.
Yes, yes, but its simple, hairless mind
is consumed with fear.
Bright eyes, hello.
According to your calendar, this is a gear 2525.
2525?
Is man still alive?
Is it woman survived?
Can you pick your son, pick your daughter, too,
from the bottom of a long glass tube?
Sadly, no, this has not come to pass.
And yet, apes have progressed far.
Why, who can say when one is--
Whoa, whoa, in the year 25--
Doctor!
Your research?
[Barking]
Anyway, what you need to know is that humans
are a degraded species and apes rule the world.
Anything else?
Well, you gotta understand, we've been through a lot here.
First, this mad scientist holds his captive
and makes us watch bad movies.
Then he tries to kill us, but we escape
and get hurled to the edge of the universe.
And now we do get back to Earth, but it's 500 years
of the future and it's just been really hard.
Can I just say at this point, I don't remember any of this
and I've certainly never met this large man here.
Get your hands off me.
So maybe you can help us get back to our own time,
Mr. Orangutan?
Oran-- orangutan?
I am not an orangutan, no.
I am a mountain gorilla.
My name is Bobo, Professor Bobo, son of Coco,
and heir to the lineage of Godo, Bogo, and Chim Chim.
And I'm Peanut.
Dr. Peanut.
Ow, ow!
Anyway, we can't help you, I'm sorry.
A planet where apes evolved from men?
Well, it's maybe a little more complicated than that,
but that is the broad outline, yes.
You did it.
You finally did it.
Damn us all to hell, yes, yes.
It's a mad house.
A mad house, I know.
[laughs]
Well then, are we all set?
All on the same page?
Good.
Human civilization is dead and apes rule the world.
Everything you ever knew or loved is no more.
Well, your movie this week--
Movies? What are you doing?
Why are you showing us movies?
It's ape law.
The lawgiver brings us these films.
Do you not know the lawgiver?
They have no soul.
You're right.
Well, your movie this week is The Revenge of the Creature.
It is a sequel to The Creature of the Black Lagoon.
There are monkeys in this movie.
Indeed.
[laughter]
Great.
Five hundred years in the future and we're still watching bad movies.
Here we go again.
You know, although, Crowe, you seem different.
Really?
Yeah, I don't know what it is.
I said forget it.
Maybe you seem different every day.
Do I harp on that?
Well, I thought you didn't remember me.
I don't.
[buzzer]
Movie time!
[music]
Apes, can you believe it?
Fits right in with my week.
Jesus, man.
Hey, this is gonna be fun, a movie.
Oh, this is what we did for seven years.
The Randy Johnson story.
The creature's gonna penny your locker door and put a bucket of water on top.
He'll be exacting his revenge on John Agar, Laurie Nelson, John Braunfield.
[laughter]
Boy, it sure clouded up fast, huh?
Almost like rain over Nestor Paiva.
[music]
Well, I'd say the creature organized himself quite a little team to exact his revenge.
This is Storm Center for slow moving credits are headed toward Annandale, Lester Prairie, Circle Pines.
Gowns, there's gonna be gowns in this movie.
Hurray!
[laughter]
[music]
Oh, we so gratefully acknowledge the most generous cooperation of Marineland like it was so hard.
Marineland is looking for a few good belugas.
[laughter]
Cabia?
[music]
Music supervision by Joseph Gersendjian.
Great supervision. Give me a needle drop on some This Island Earth music.
And somebody whip up some gowns.
[music]
Live from Lincoln Center, a tributary to the upper Amazon with Johnny Carson, Stephen Eady.
Vice President Al Gore.
Buddy Hackett.
Don Rickles.
And Beck.
[music]
Tributary.
Yes.
Oh, hey, listen to that. I heard the ooh, ah, ah, ah, ah creature.
[music]
Oh, the kind of Amazon's good.
Buckadell's good.
[laughter]
Cram it, nature.
[music]
Wow, woops.
You know, when the tall ships come into the Amazon, it's just magnificent.
[music]
Oh, the trees are leaking.
He's got a crack crew. When they bend down, you can see their cracks.
[laughter]
Hey, they're going tubing on the Amazon.
[music]
Stop battening things down. It's all batten for God's sake.
Stay here tonight, Natto.
Would you like some chiggers?
We go to the Black Lagoon in the morning.
I'll get you some supper now.
What are we having tonight?
Oh, big surprise. What we didn't finish last night.
Carp balls, drizzled with my own perspiration.
What I'd give for a tall, cold beer.
Or a short, warm blonde.
Like Denny Dillon?
Kill me. Prehistoric master. Maybe there's no such thing.
You find him, mister. I'll catch him.
It doesn't look good for a conservative institution like Ocean Harbor to circus in your arm when not to deliver.
You're smart, you won't worry about it.
There is a gill, man. We'll take it.
Establish. Build.
It's a phony.
Backstory.
Bosses out his dough.
Reveal.
George.
Motivation.
[growling]
A swimming grizzly.
Hey, Lucas.
Yes, Mr. Johnson?
Oh, belly flop.
Ah, it's a crocodile.
Huh, you think maybe that is it?
Oh, no. The thing you are looking for can break that in two.
Eh, go put on your sports bra.
North Americanos are crazy.
If he's dead, you waste your money.
If he's alive, maybe you'll be sorry you find him.
Eh, there isn't a fish alive I can't handle.
Who says he's a fish?
Can we please kill him?
What a character.
Show me the way to go home.
[laughing]
This is what, Fox. Doesn't it ever cool off here?
Never.
If you want to go back, out of your service.
Not till we get the, uh, whatever it is.
Then we'll go back.
More tawny port?
He won't rest easy till he's got in the tank back at Ocean Harbor.
What for do you want to do this?
So people can come and stare at the manfish?
To be some crazy scientist?
For this, you're going to risk your lives?
Who said anything about risking lives?
Job. Technical job.
Oh.
Shall we?
Maybe then you got a book that going to tell you how to do this thing.
Now look, we're not paying you to make jokes.
No joke.
Tomorrow we're going to be in the lagoon.
We will go down in the water.
Then it's no longer time for talking.
So maybe it's better we talk now, eh?
Well, I got to go make the lagoon a little blacker.
[laughing]
Okay. Go ahead.
Last year I came to this place with a body of scientists.
Also brave and highly technical people.
How many odors does he put off at once?
In the end, five persons were dead.
He's an enchanting monologist.
Still dead.
Nice spice rack anyway.
Were they equipped for the capture?
No. No, we are.
So?
Sue.
I'd like to ask you something.
Do you think I'm cute?
I'm not very educated person.
This gill man.
Vince the gill man?
The thing I've seen with my eyes.
It doesn't belong in our world.
It should have died out long before a man was born.
Still it exists.
Why?
Well, I'll try to explain it to you.
You smell bad.
Sometimes a species gets isolated in time.
Testify.
If the conditions are right, it reproduces itself.
Naughty.
Without change.
Okay.
It's difficult.
The chapter of evolution.
Way back, there must have been some major link
between marine and terrestrial life.
We think it was manimal.
It's just possible that this is it.
Tell him how handsome I am.
Well, that's all there is to it.
Can we talk about booze?
Now I tell you what I believe.
I believe I look good in a thong.
This beast exists because it is stronger than the thing that you call evolution.
We call it maize.
In it is some force of life.
A demon driving it through millions of centuries.
God, I'm handsome.
He does not surrender so easily to weaklings like you and me.
Yes, but I'm handsome.
This is the thing that you hunt for.
Think on it.
I'll get your sopa pias now.
Is he a purple martin's nesting in his ears?
Poor lad, gentlemen.
I've got to go douse myself in right guard.
Well, I'm handsome.
And that, kiddies, is our fairy story for tonight.
You tuck him in and I'll do the dishes.
Joe, maybe he's right.
Maybe I do have the feet of a dancer.
Back in Florida.
We got beaches and stuff.
You don't suppose that they expect us to lose our lives over this thing.
Maybe we got no business to be here at all.
Want to play some cards?
No.
Chutes and ladders?
No, I think I'll try to get some sleep.
You'd better do the same.
Oh, I'll sleep fine.
I'm handsome.
No imagination.
Could we pitch in and buy that guy an ass?
Well, if you hear funny noises, it's not what you think.
Ooh, I think I heard a splash when his head hit the pillow.
We now return to our tributary to the upper amazon with Celine Dion.
Tom Kenneth Galbraith.
Tom Wopat.
Gerald Ford and the Statlers.
Starship.
I swear, the guy was this big if he was an inch.
I mean it.
Regrets, I've heard of you.
Ooh, that's nuts.
I think after a while birds would just stay out of there.
With Karen Black.
Thomas Aquinas.
Queen Latifah.
Nico Machiavelli.
Vanilla Ice.
Gabriel Garcia Marquez.
Dr. Ruth Westheimer.
Martin Buber and Junior Samples.
Christina Pickles and Franz Lis.
Bonnie Vidilia and Gregor Mendel.
Geraldine Ferraro and Carrot Top.
Nardo!
Don't have to dog!
Here I am! I'm the creature!
Esther Williams didn't age too well.
Bring the net down. Lower.
Good.
The Americano does the rest.
Part of the NAFTA agreement, I think.
You get that net secured, Joe, and we got the entrance sealed off.
Well, let's go.
Wait. Ow. Ow.
You got some lip skin in the... Ow!
All this because he dropped his favorite guitar pick overboard.
He would be helpless as a baby.
This baby was born in that suit.
He's taken pretty good care of himself up to now.
Now he's different, my friend.
That's one small step for bogus science.
Ah, truck two-seat, dude.
Shrivel. Shrivel. Shrivel more.
Somebody got a flush.
Creature of Calumet Harbor.
Hey, Bob.
Hey, Ted. How's it going?
Power pinged.
Lucas isn't getting you scared, is he?
With Edna St. Vincent Millay and Toboggan...
It's over.
Oh, music cue. Sorry.
Man's threatened the deep-sea divers squirts ink.
Oh, Dino, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
Oh, darn, Dino.
Bring him in. Bring him in.
Play him. Play him.
Let him swallow the guy.
Give me your wallet.
I want your wallet and your PIN number.
A brief pause on the music.
And now back to our program.
I want that St. Christopher medal.
I will admit the alligator I snapped in half was half-snapped already,
and I got him just at the right angle, so...
Joe, can you hear me?
I'm on goal.
Hey, look. He's coming up.
He's bringing his money.
Don't let him wrap Joe around the anchor line.
Come on. Let me just swim a few times over your legs and bingo, we got kids.
With Martin Heidegger and Men Without Hats.
Bro. Let's see it.
I'm getting free cable.
Quick. Back up the files.
I'm forever blowing bubbles.
He's the only fish with a butt.
It's like going underwater with a urinal on your head.
Hey, can I get a latte out of the back of your head?
Real successful first dive, Ted.
I'm glad he didn't get you.
Hold the pin, Lucas, you see.
No, don't pull the pin. He'll blow up.
Really? Mexico wants our nuclear waste.
They somehow know he likes Italian almond cookies?
Ah, well, that's the last of your sweat.
I hope you ain't going to blow up my boat, Mr. Johnson.
Like my wife, she's not much, but she's all I have.
It's just enough dynamite in these cans to stun anything below the surface.
If that thing's alive, this ought to do the trick.
This guy can get married and I can't even get a date.
You do it easy, huh?
Let's kill him.
You ready?
Here goes napping.
Ah, the Charlton Heston fish locator.
He's probably way over in the mauve lagoon.
I got it.
♪ A-O wives, get it? ♪
♪ A-O wives ♪
I do, yeah.
You even maimed I'm handsome.
He doesn't know I'm looking at him, but oh, God, he's foxy.
Think anybody at the Rockefeller Foundation questioned the dynamite line item?
You got any nuclear devices on board?
Well, no sign of them.
Maybe this time we are lucky and he is dead, huh?
At long last.
Kill him!
Got hold of a bad egret.
There he is.
Or someone like him.
By golly, you're right. There he is.
Come on, Lucas. Let's go get him.
Always I got a bad look.
Sure you tie him up good.
Oh, and tie up the creature, too.
This is the first telephoto of the fantastic find received from Rio de Janeiro.
Ah, he's married.
The creature is in a coma.
Has been ever since its capture in an isolated Amazon lagoon.
Right now it's being flown to Florida's famed Ocean Harbor Oceanarium.
Yay!
Where the experts hope to restore it to consciousness.
Is that an oil filter above his head?
This creature has required some split-second timing.
It can exist out of water for only a few minutes at a stretch.
The capture of the Gill Man has created the greatest scientific stirs since the explosion of the atomic bomb.
Further information is anxiously awaited in colleges and universities throughout the world.
Like this.
Ah, the Gill Man goes to Harvard.
By Neil, that's wonderful.
You have such a vibrant color sense for a four-year-old.
Can I roller skate now?
I think this one is even good enough to show to your friends.
Look, I'm drunk, I'm suicidal, and I want you out of here, okay?
All right, lesson's over.
Now, turn around, Neil.
Turn around, turn around. Sit down.
All right.
And, evolve.
Open your mouth.
Come back here, you doofa.
Oh, that's a boy.
All right, now, cover your eyes. Cover your eyes.
I'm gonna change my bra.
That's a good boy. Now, stand up. Stand up.
Put your arms over your head and...
Hey, they're serving monkey brains again and...
Good morning, Dr. Ferguson.
Morning, Neil.
His butt's wet.
How's he doing?
Fine.
Neil, what do you think of your work?
The script said, "Ha ha ha ha ha ha."
It's just amazing.
He's really as bright as a child.
Well, as bright as a two or three-year-old, anyway.
But remember, we're supposed to find out what the difference is
between the intelligence of an ape and a human being.
And at the rate he's going, sometimes I wonder if there is any difference.
Doc, would you come here a minute?
Sure.
Man, I stained his lab coat so bad.
Hey!
Didn't you say that among the lower animals,
there were no natural enemies, as long as they were well fed?
Yeah, something like that.
Wow.
Well, maybe so, Doc,
but there were four rats in there when I changed my lights.
Now there's only three.
Punk.
It's my considerate opinion that rat number four is sitting inside that cat.
Are you sure you fed them all this morning?
Sure. I always feed them.
Seeing as how I've got a .44 Magnum in my pocket,
the most powerful hand in the world.
How'd he get in here?
This guy's bad.
This is his first and last movie here.
Cleet.
Cleet, here's the most important news,
the greatest scientific find since the Peking Man.
What you got, Max?
I'm on Earth, a natural blonde.
Welcome to Happy Labs.
We acted that Devonian relic Dr. Reed reported last year.
You're kidding.
I am kidding. It's Happy Labs.
I think you should be thinking about going down to Ocean Harbor.
You wouldn't have any trouble.
They know your work down there.
I wonder if it's a picture of Gypsy up on the wall.
Cleet, you could be the first man to scientifically study a creature
that by all the laws of nature should have died a quarter of a million years ago.
I'm gonna write down that blonde joke.
That was good.
He asked the dean for a leave of absence.
What else?
That's Cleet.
McCall.
Joe, Johnson.
Hello.
How are you, Lou, Mr. Foster?
Never better, Joe.
Old country's talking about that catch of yours.
That right?
That ought to be worth a race then.
Brought some cow and brunette dancers with me too.
What's this I hear about you getting lost?
Just a few scratches.
Hey, we'll bring him right up.
On second thought, let's go back.
Let's go down there, boys.
Now keep him straight.
I think he's dead.
Guide him in there easily and watch his head that doesn't hit on that bullcat.
I really think he's dead.
All right.
Move him through slowly.
Guy keeps a brace of fin gay Nazis around apparently.
Mark just a little.
All right.
All right, take it away.
Does it even occur to them to check for a zipper?
The new wench is quieter.
What?
I said the new wench.
Fresh from the Amazon to your table overnight.
Okay, swing it in.
Just get an electric guitar.
It'll take some time.
Flanging twires.
Rita snots.
Yeah, yeah, Rita snots.
Don't go there, man.
Corda snots.
I gots to know.
Just let it lie.
Corda snots.
Oh heck, crew, I'll just say it.
You're different.
Oh yeah, oh yeah.
Well then how come I don't remember you?
Corda snots.
Ah, forget it.
I'm knocking off for a ho ho.
Oh, sir, how long is this going to take?
We have to get back to our own time.
Well, Mike, jerking around must have caused a flame out.
Your pigeon tube is shot.
Jimmy Caw Caws grow over it in three places.
Oh, ten days.
Ah, you have five days.
Okay then, two weeks.
Well, you just said ten days.
I forgot I have two vacation days in there.
I don't know why you don't just use the nets.
Nanites?
You know, tiny robotic self-replicating machines no bigger than a molecule.
I didn't know we had any.
Where are they?
Well, they're kind of everywhere.
You're sitting on about a million of them.
They self-replicate like men.
Okay, come on over here.
Oh, okay.
All right.
Hey, where did you get a magnetic resonance scanning and tunneling microscope?
A fellow named Helmut.
Lived here about 20 years.
I remember him quite fondly, in fact.
Hello, anybody in here?
Hello, anybody in there?
My name's Mike.
Does that matter?
Yes, hello Mike.
Connecting.
I am Nanite Engineer Device, or NED.
Please jump in the nature of the problematic substrate or aversive condition, which you
would like corrected or in the – Mike, hold on.
Here comes Wade.
Hello, Wade.
Yes, hello, Ned.
Hello, Mike.
As Ned was saying, beyond our copious and continual self-replication resident order
is our task in the precise correction of aversive conditions and the implementation of appropriate
technology relevant to that condition.
But I'll let Ned here fill in the blanks.
Thank you, Wade.
As Wade was saying –
Hold on there, Pards.
I can't understand a word you're saying.
Can you simplify it a little?
Of course.
I'm sorry, my manners forgive me.
What can we do you for?
Ah, that's better.
Well, you see, the ship is broken and it won't go.
Can you fix it?
Of course.
We'd love to serve.
Initiate molecular diagnostic array –
Initiating molecular diagnostic array –
Go, go, go, go.
So, Crowe, where'd you get these little guys anyway?
Well, I want two at a county fair a while back and well –
How many are there now, would you say?
Let's see.
Last ballpark count, about 218 billion trillion.
Well, enough to populate several small planets.
The rape routine, read embezzimous anomalous crude technology,
blocking access board C3 on minor jettison jettison.
Whoa.
Well, I should mention that their ultimate goal is to take over the universe.
Oh, yeah, it figures.
We'll be right back.
You okay up there?
Keep it coming, boys.
Keep it coming right in here.
You doing okay?
Yeah, we need somebody who can keep them overnight at his house.
Keep it coming.
Raise it up a little.
Oh.
Oh, could you guys get my Dramamine, please?
Now down.
The next step is the brining tank.
After that, he's aged in oak caskets up to three years.
All right, hold it. Hold it.
That's good.
Just put him in with the minnows, I guess.
Hey, three Jack rubies.
I got some bad news for you, Mr. Foster.
The Gill man?
Yeah, been in a coma ever since we captured him.
But he's still alive.
Hey, just about.
Look, Sinatra.
Look, Joe, you can't do this to me.
Why, I've got every man, woman, and child in this civilized world
waiting to meet the Gill man.
Say it ain't so, Joe.
The hotel's booked for 50 miles around here.
I've got the radio, the TV.
Louie, speeches aren't going to do any good now.
We'll put him in the receiving tank.
We'll see what happens.
Come on, let's get rolling, Mac.
Okay, Joe.
Wow, suddenly all the pressure's on the creature to perform.
Say, what's our job in this, talkie?
Oh, great.
Please spare us nothing.
There must have been an intense interest in stevedores at this time.
I suppose we might describe this, ladies and gentlemen,
as the creature's official entry into the 20th century.
Let's give it up for the creature.
If it lives, if it lives at all,
and become the object of scientific study.
Why is he dead?
Motherhood boxcar.
The man who captured the creature will be able to bring it out of its comatose condition.
Joe will now lay on the creature in an attempt to revive it.
A lot of people out there, you gotta wake up and snap an alligator in half, okay?
Okay, take it away.
The creature's got a great body.
I mean, he'd look good in a double-breasted suit is what I'm saying.
Whatever.
Hey, boys, look up here.
Man, look at that thing.
This way, Mr. Lagoon.
Will he come out of it?
Too early to tell.
Scooby? Scooby Dooby?
Does he got a thing?
[snorting]
Ms. Dobson, may I have a word with you?
You left your electric toothbrush.
I have here, Ms. Helen Dobson, one of the prettiest young ladies
that's ever been my pleasure to interview.
Thanks.
Ms. Dobson was a science major at Belmont University in Texas.
Now, well, perhaps I better get her to explain it to you.
What brings you to the ocean area, Ms. Dobson?
I'm here to gather material for my master's thesis.
I'm studying ichthyology.
Ichthyology? That's a $10 word.
How about explaining it to us?
Well, ichthyology is the study of fish.
I see.
Is that water there?
I noticed that Joe Hayes out here has the gill man down in the water
and he's walking him around.
That seems to be a strange thing to do.
Is there any particular reason for it?
Well, that's the way they revive sharks and other large fish.
And since this creature has gills, they're using the same method.
Great interview.
Fill, stretch.
He forces water into the mouth from which it flows over the gill.
I notice you're bewitching a man into your web of decedent lies.
As the water traverses past the gills,
fine blood vessels on the surface of the gills release the carbon dioxide
and pick up a dissolved oxygen from the water,
which exits from the fish through the gill slit.
I see. Well, do you think it will work in this particular case?
Well, I'm no prophet.
Well, thank you very much for talking to us, Miss Dobson.
Okay, erase the tape. Forget it.
How does it look, Joe?
Smelling really bad.
Can't tell yet, Lou.
The very next summer.
Everybody's drifted over to the World of Barnacles exhibit.
Boo Radley, Herald Tribune.
How long has he been walking this thing?
Piss off.
Last two hours.
What a way to make a living.
Just flush him.
You get your hands off my blowhole, it might help.
The gill man carries a lot of tension in his face, you know what I'm saying?
His arm. I saw it. It did move.
Did not.
Watch it up there. He's starting to move.
Engine's on. Contact.
Oh, that is good chlorine.
Great, I gotta change my name to Creature of the Edinburgh Park Kitty Pool.
Why doesn't he get out?
Get those ropes ready. I wanna get out of here as soon as I get a line on him.
I got a Kiwanis lunch I gotta get to.
[mimics car noises]
Oh, did I miss my cue?
I want Joe Frazier.
Do they really need a flash from the middle of Florida in the day?
That's my cue.
Open creature swim until 5pm.
Help me, I'm a freshwater creature.
This never happened in ichthyologistics.
Yeah, you got him, Joe. He's yours. No problem.
A little help here.
Oh my stars, how disappointing.
Thank God the milkmen showed up.
I wanted smoke, you bastard.
Hey, don't grab ass in the kitty pool.
Fellow milkmen down.
All these tourists are certainly getting their two bits worth.
Brilliant suggestion. I was gonna lead them out to sea.
Henry Rollins to the rescue.
Okay, I've got his wrist. Get those cuts fixed up right away.
Alright, alright.
I've got his pancreas down here.
He can use that little bag for his fine wash of his later.
How gracious. Oh, how beautiful.
Ladies and gentlemen, our ocean harbor technicians are about to move the Gill-man from the receiving tank into the larger permanent tank.
Mr. Joe Hayes is in charge of the operation.
Open up the gate.
To the Schwartz and Anderson families who did lose children, our sincere apologies.
Hey, honey. Hey, sweetie. Come on over here. You got some nice scales on you.
I'll do it myself.
I'm treating him like Bobby Seale.
Sawfish.
Yeah, me too. There's lots of them.
Always wear eye protection when you're mean.
Alright, lats out at 8.30. A few flakes of food will be thrown on top of the water each morning.
You have the right to remain amphibious. If you cannot afford an ichthyologist, the court will appoint one on your behalf.
Cigarettes are not to be used as currency. Any fish caught using cigarettes as currency will spend a night in the live box.
With Benazir Butoh and Flavor Flay.
Pro, please.
Oh, sorry. Misplaced music cue there. Nothing happened. Sorry.
My partner, the milkman, was a day away from retirement just to run up to the Hendersons, and that was it.
The gillman now has only three minutes of air. Let's see how he does.
A parade of tiny, upsetting shorts.
Everything alright? Wait till they're all out of the tank. I'm not taking any chances.
I can still get into the shorts I wore in kindergarten.
These fish really should shower before getting into the pool.
Oh.
Hey, buddy. How you doing? How's it going?
Hey, new guy.
Hey, bite me!
I hope that chain holds. Don't worry about that chain.
Thanks for allaying my worries.
Ah, jeez. Damn Denver poop.
I hate these things.
Ladies and gentlemen, Miss Diana Ross.
Ladies and gentlemen, to Ocean Harbor.
On this, the first day of public exhibit of the world famous gillman.
Yeah, look at that over there.
And there's stuff there.
And then stuff happened over there that I saw and that stuff.
Our attendants will be pleased to answer your questions as you tour the wonders of the deep.
Sitting with me in the booth here today, Burt Blyloven.
Goldfish exhibit still draws millions every year.
Suddenly we got an Aaron Copeland thing going on.
Look at what your little friend to play with. He's so cute.
Oh my God. Oh no.
Way smarter than you. If we had opposable fins, we'd kick your ass.
Yeah, Pha loves Pa. Give me a damn fish.
Have any me-safe tuna?
I'm done with your taxes. When do you want them?
Hey, fish. Get your fish. Pass this down, will you, buddy? Thanks a lot.
Hey, nice rig. What kind of lens are you using? Carl Zeiss 10 millimeter prime?
Oh, very nice.
Very shortly now the field man will be fed.
Scientists are still investigating his diet.
They found the creature reluctant to eat these fish that are swimming about him in the tank.
He seems to like Honey Nut Cheerios.
Hey, we could use a wet vac down here.
Aquarium of the damned.
Which one is the fish?
Be my love, for no one else can end.
It was a real break finding you here.
As I've been stalking you for several days.
Look, I'm not one of those specialists who fails to appreciate the other fellas' feel.
Although personally I think we're over specialized.
Go away.
What's getting us so, we have experts who concentrate only on the lower section of a specimen's left ear.
Oh, he's Stacy Keachin.
Well, I must tell you, I know something about your work.
And I was quite impressed when I heard you were coming.
You're not at all like I expected.
You're even worse.
I'm glad I disappointed you.
Don't let the smile touch your eyes.
That's the rule of John Agar.
Hey, I was supposed to meet a small grouper over here.
You guys seen him?
Hey, uh, zip me, will ya?
Sorry, fish didn't come in today.
We got bologna sandwiches.
Oh boy, oh boy, lunch.
Normally they got a buffet, but hey, I'm hungry.
Mmm.
I quit.
Hey, come back.
I just want to give you a tip.
What delicious...
Oh wow, a fish.
Boy, am I stuffed.
He's saving all the fish.
Gonna make a bomb from eel pout and bluegill.
Yes, I'm the rare blue porgy.
Oh, you're looking at the gill man, of course.
I think he's got some shame issues with his food.
Hey, swimming with me.
There's fish, see?
I see fish.
Yeah.
He kind of looks like Martin Van Buren.
I think he overdid it with his nail wraps.
Out of my life, this is my shot.
I wonder if he works for scale.
Oh, hello.
Hello.
He's not much on table manners, is he?
I deductioned that.
Come on, let's get out of here before the crowd runs over us.
All right.
What are you doing for dinner tonight?
Eating that with you.
You don't waste any time, do you?
I've only got two weeks.
But you came here to work.
Any time a man can combine business with pleasure,
he's batting 500 in my league.
Well, slugging percentage, I mean,
and if you figure in walks, I...
The bathrooms are really confusing.
They're marked mollusks and crustaceans.
Ah, the Schmanke brothers at Sea World.
They've got cabin for some coffee.
Jack.
Now I'll start all over again.
Stop saying what are you doing for dinner tonight?
Well, I haven't thought about it, sir.
Then that's it.
Now, where are you staying?
At the Star Motel.
Great, so am I.
Hey, professor!
Your wife just called.
Wait for me!
Uh-oh, I've been afraid of this.
That Joe Hayes is an A-number-one wolf.
Avoid him.
It'll be difficult, but it can be done.
Well, I...
Let go!
Aren't you gonna wait for him?
What, let Mr. America cut into my cake?
Wow.
What's the matter, old timer poof-out?
Out of cake?
You can walk these brain boys to fast,
tell them they can't take it.
You know, drawing upstairs with no stamina.
My God.
Good to see you, Cleen.
I heard you were in town.
You too.
I understand you're gonna be here for a couple of weeks, huh?
Yeah, that's right.
That's tough.
You won't have a chance to enjoy the good things in life.
It's endless March music in the background.
Ah!
Sorry, Joe.
She just made a date with me.
Look, I'm a huge lesbian.
Why?
Could you just please...
Well, yes.
Oh, but you can join us, Joe, if you want to.
No, thanks.
I'll give the professor his chance.
I don't like to take advantage of amateurs.
See you later.
Yeah, after he disappoints her bitterly tonight,
I'll show her some real moves tomorrow.
Ladies and gentlemen, in producing Flippy,
the educated fortress.
I do not accept my slave name.
Edna, where are you?
Hi.
How are the depth charge?
Flippy has been taught to retrieve objects on command.
Or receive swift and severe punishment.
Will you please hold on to it this time?
I'm not gonna get it again.
Now for a finale.
Flippy will raise the flag.
Well, I was gonna recite the wasteland,
but I guess I'll just raise the flag.
Well, it's better than killing ourselves.
This is what my father is doing in his grave.
Stop.
He's eating. It's funny.
Well, where have you been, boy?
Smelling another dog's paw. Why?
Oh, I guess I'll give her an introduction.
Professor, this is Chris.
My one true love and favorite boyfriend.
Look, I like you a lot.
Well, it's all right, boy.
I'm gonna get you some food.
Well, it's all right, boy. He won't bite you.
Aw, come on, boy.
Riss off, Ruster.
Hey, you're a good old dog.
Does he always travel with you?
No, no.
He picked me up a couple of weeks ago.
I was here watching the porpoises,
and he made a pass at me.
Didn't you, boy?
I think you misread some signals.
So, a finale apparently does not mean the end.
I don't care about that.
Ah, the Immaculate Reception.
Please, please leave me an atom of my dignity.
If he gets any smarter, he'll start talking.
He talks all right.
We're just not smart enough to understand him.
Hi.
You think Chris is smarter than Flippy, Professor?
I doubt it.
A porpoise has a very large and well-developed brain.
Hi.
In fact, his intelligence lies somewhere
between a chimpanzee and a dog.
Hi.
How smart is the Gillman?
Well, that's what I'm here to find out.
Hi.
His reflexes are like his behavior pattern,
his capacity to learn, his response to stimuli.
Hi.
Oh, it sounds exciting.
I hope I'll be able to help.
Thanks. I'm sure you will.
Here we go.
Oh, I gotta drop some pounds.
Okay, once more.
He's guarded by Hitler Youth.
All right, Flippy.
You may now return to your private store.
Flippy, the budget porpoise.
Testing.
One, two, three, four.
What are we fighting for?
Testing. One, two, three, four.
I have a new craze, camera dipping.
Oh, hello, creature.
Testing. One, two, three, four.
Hey, your bottom end's a little muddy.
You might want to EQ that up a little.
Testing. One, two, three, four.
Is it for me?
No, it's not for me.
Never is.
The speaker must be working.
He's reacting to it down there.
He's doing a tarantella.
Be sure your throat mic is tight.
I don't have a throat mic. I'm a creature.
Do you need any milk, sir?
Be sure and keep that volume up.
His shorts are practically inside of him.
Now, the most important thing is not to become so interested you get careless.
Oh, you don't have to worry about that.
I'm not interested at all.
Nothing goes wrong. You head straight for the surface, you understand?
That's up, right?
All right, let's go.
He looks like a Chippendales dancer.
No, no, he doesn't.
Sure he can use this.
But I am a drum major.
I guess we haven't much choice.
All right, now, let's go over it once more.
Wait.
You're to wait for the right moment and then push the food cage within his reach.
As he reaches for it, you're to say "stop" into your throat microphone.
He won't know what it means, so I'll condition him by shocking him with a bull prod.
Right?
Right.
Bob, hand me this when I get in the water with you.
So to review, I should check my makeup, go shopping and talk about boys, right?
Sorry.
I can't see. I can't breathe.
She's got a bunch of snuff containers on her belt.
What do those do?
The heck?
I'm in the...
Coming.
Oh, hi.
May I help you, sir?
Oh, right.
Okay, hold on a sec.
Tom?
Yo.
A gentleman here to see you.
Seems a little cheesed off.
Hmm.
Does he have an eye patch?
Yeah.
Tentacles?
Yes.
A snappy dresser?
Pretty stylish, yeah.
Oh, boy.
I don't know the guy.
I told him to leave his car.
Bricks, bro.
I'm not starbo.
Tom, he's gonna demolecularize the whole ship.
Would you get out here and talk to him?
All right.
Neck, neck, neck, neck.
Even...
Phil, how are you old rescueal, you?
Bricks, bro.
Bricks.
Bah, wah.
I know, Phil.
Bricks.
Dab, I get extremely dab, dab.
I know, but...
Bricks, bro.
I'm not dab.
Mocha, mocha.
Bricks.
Of course, Phil.
I see your point, but it was an honest mistake.
As you folks like to say, "Brin, da, tah, my gah, tah, tah."
Mike, what were you saying the other day?
What was that?
Oh, I was just telling him, "Ricks, flock, nah."
Get up there, get up there.
All right, Phil.
Geez, the whole Andromeda Galaxy revolves around this guy.
Mike, there's a sizable titanium casket down here somewhere.
Oh.
It contains some treasure that Phil apparently can't live without.
Would you...
This is filled with French...
Forget about that.
Just jettison it out the airlock.
Will you?
Okay, right.
Sure.
All right.
Phil, what a big baby you are sometimes.
Bricks, blah, blah.
What, starbo?
Starflake, pal.
Geez, things are tough all over.
Aw, starbait me.
Just blow, will ya?
Pying out loud with a baby.
Tom, that was filled with French vanilla pudding.
Oh, yeah?
Well, that's legal tender where Phil comes from, my friend.
Men die like stink bugs for just a fraction of the treasure I had there.
Just what did you do out at the edge of the universe anyway?
Well, things happen, boy-o.
Don't trouble your pretty little noggin over it.
I just know I've lived, my friend.
That's me, that's my nature.
Just gotta be it all, see it all.
Oh, we got movies, so tell me more about it later.
Just gotta rise and tighten up my trunk and keep an eye on this girl.
Yep, you know, I've been a rambler and a gambler and I guess I always will.
B, B, one, right.
Okay, gotcha.
I've got the sandwiches.
[Music]
Me.
Whoa, I've gained a lot of weight in my feet.
Nice abs.
The creature's got the six-pack working.
Here he comes.
Be careful, Creed.
Hey, guys, what's with the flag bolt?
Oh, wow, geez.
That was lesson number one.
He knows the prods can hurt him.
Put the cage down and stay close to the wall.
Right.
I'll see if the creatures have had it.
What was I supposed to do?
What the?
Huh?
Try juggling.
Why do I let him tell me what to do?
I'm pretty darn sciency too, you know.
He likes me.
Gotta play it cool.
Get back, Helen.
Here he comes.
What is it today?
Stakeling weenie?
Oh, it's fish.
Thanks.
No.
Man, I asked for a schmear.
Oh, come on.
He's the Mangala Institute for Marine Research.
Look, you and me got off on the wrong foot.
Why don't we just have a little time?
Oh, come on.
Hate to use this.
I love to use this.
So how come you're not shocking the grouper?
He's no prince.
No.
It's a success.
We've made him afraid of flag poles.
He's learning fast.
Shall we try it again?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
No, that's enough for now.
Let's take the cage out.
From now on, we're the only ones who'll feed him.
Oh, fine.
Men always know what to do.
Jailbreak at ten.
Pass it on.
Ah, phooey on you.
Yeah, well, your oil's a little low.
Yes, the famous and cinematically groundbreaking
climbing out of the pool scene from Revenge of the Creature.
That was fine.
Now you better get out of that rig and...
And into my rig.
We have a date for dinner tonight.
I'll bring the prod.
Have her home early.
Good night, kids.
Oh, God, I'm so late.
I'll be right there, guys.
I seem to be, I don't know, attached to something here.
Hang on.
And all his woodland buddies are coming to help him.
[humming]
Nothing on tonight, just the fish channel.
I'm innocent, I tell ya.
Yeah, we're all innocent in this tank, buddy.
Hey, no bitches, no bitches.
Miss Betty Furness.
No, we can't cash a check here, sir.
This is the commercial window.
You know, I was thinking maybe you and I could maybe get to get...
You like sushi.
Why don't you just marry the stupid Gilmore?
Hi.
I don't care what the joke writers say.
It takes longer for a man to dress.
You got more to put on.
I was talking.
How's he doing?
Fine.
We were.
Come on, let's get out of here.
All right.
Okay, then, we'll just talk later, okay?
Okay?
[singing in Italian]
Later at the Chelsea Hotel.
Fish spotting.
Jeez, at this point, he threatens to disappear into his hat.
Here's the Mickey Finn, Professor.
Good.
And here's my area.
Takes about five minutes for this stuff to work.
Then he'll be gentle as a baby.
I suppose.
Fine scientists you are getting squeamish about doping a fish.
You're squeamish about your bathing suit.
Oh, gross, he's in a naval enlargement.
Give me that.
Jeez.
Can't complain about the service here.
There isn't any.
Hey, who wants to swap lunches?
Never mind.
He's got it.
That's certain something, that indefinable it.
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy, oh boy.
Hey, wait a minute.
Demerol.
Oh, I gotta go pray to the porcelain coral reef.
At this point, the swimsuits are merely a formality.
Let's go.
Right.
Air tanks by Hebrew National Franks.
Let's see, what part of John Agar haven't I seen?
Oh, his butt cheeks.
Thanks, John.
Luca Brasi sleeps with us.
So happy together.
Ouch.
Sorry, that's bad.
Thank you.
What you gonna do?
You gonna go talk to the creature?
'Cause he's a nice guy, but he's got a bad temper,
so you gotta be careful with the creature.
Hey, I met one of you guys one time.
You pulled me into a boat and I was really scared and stuff,
but then the guy was really nice and stuff,
so it was really cool.
Fish.
She doesn't like me.
Here, here's a nice indiglo for you.
Thank you.
Bad boys, bad boys, watcha gonna do?
Watcha gonna...
This is...
Ha, fucks.
Let's see, inseam 34, waist 91.
This thing kicked me out of steak doll face.
Hey, what goes on here?
I'm science.
Oh, well...
Every second, millions of electric impulses
lead from one cell of the brain to another.
That's gooby.
Making our minds and moods what they are.
Dooby.
You see, those wires on the Gill man
pick up these impulses and register them here on the chart.
Yeah.
Naturally, we'd learn a lot more about the creature
if we could test him while he was awake.
Well, my dear girl, everybody knows that when you're asleep,
the brain stops working.
No more so than the heart does.
The brain waves become irregular,
like those of the insane.
You mean I'm crazy when I'm asleep?
No more so than when you're awake.
Oh, he looks like a rat of NIMH.
Hey, creature's got his own letterhead.
Plays well with other children.
Oh, she's back at the Ponds Institute.
Say ah.
He looks like a drive-in.
This is not Greg Norman.
This shark juice habit is getting out of hand.
I'm really doing it.
I'm really actually doing science.
Hey, Dr. Sugarbuns.
Red corpuscle content only 10% less in human blood.
Unlucleated structure.
Well, Brand X has no un-nucleated structure.
Correlation with the fish sample.
Somehow this is gonna get me into tiny swim trunks.
Every test, every reaction, it just misses me and you.
Oh, that this too-too sullied flesh should...
I smell Tatiana.
This is gonna turn into an aquatic mandingo, isn't it?
Did you bring the arc welder?
Oh, hi.
Hey.
Oh, hi. There's a creature in every window.
Hi.
Um, jeez, I had a whole thing.
Your mustache isn't so prominent.
No, no, that's not a...
Oh.
Hey, take it easy.
You freak.
You startled me.
I'm sorry.
I am weird looking.
You know, I pity him sometimes.
He's so alone.
Wee.
The only one of his kind in the world.
Well, he's like an orphan of time.
Yeah, I've been thinking about it.
You're going to...
She's right, I am. Wow.
It's risky. Too risky.
I'd sleep better if you leave him to Joe and me.
Well, haven't I been a help?
That's not what I'm talking about. It's...
You're a girl.
Well, it's just that he's so unpredictable.
If anything were to happen...
Oh, now nothing's going to happen.
Don't you think you're making your lot out of nothing?
He's chained and you have the bull prize.
Thank you.
You're only going to be here a short time
and using Joe might hold you up.
Okay, so seven-ish, the club.
Oh, they're spreading the tarpon.
Looks like the game has rained out.
Okay, here you go. Here's my ass.
Just shock the hell out of it.
Mr. Wizard, get me out of here.
Who's the baller, huh?
You gave him a bad joke last time. He's leery.
That's all right. Try it again.
That's well known that Gilman liked to play with balls on sticks.
Oh, they have a nice sunken living room in there for him.
Balls to you, Big Daddy.
What you are about to see is an illusion,
an act of prestidigitation.
Careful, honey. Careful.
Creature, honey. Globe on a stick.
Looks pretty fun, huh?
Globe, stick.
Observe me closely and for whom I'm gone.
Hello.
Sorry, I am not grasping something here.
Can you understand why I'm confused?
I forget it.
Honey, I did a scientific breakthrough thingy.
That's amazing.
Took me three weeks to teach that to a chimp.
Of course, a couple of the chimps drowned, but...
Let's try it again. Okay?
Okay, Professor.
Professor Honeytush, please.
Come on.
Yeah, why don't you just fax me the rules to your little game?
I'm gonna go pitch pennies with a sawfish.
Don't you see? It's a globe on a stick.
Come on. Come on.
Be careful, Helen. Not too close.
Come on, you puss. What are you afraid of the ball? Come on.
Come on.
Helen, get back here.
Can't you see what I'm trying to tell you, Mrs. Claypool?
I love you.
Shh.
It's worth amnesty international when you need him.
Ladies and gentlemen, the revenge has finally begun.
Yay!
Yes, the gloves are off and the benches are clear.
Oh, boy, he's got Magnuson's jersey over his head.
Well, he started it, Mom. He shocked me and stuff.
Oh, I wet myself. I guess it doesn't really matter, does it?
I know. The soundtrack is out of control.
For what it's worth, I do like ball on a stick.
They practice a peculiar brand of silence.
Man, this thing itches.
Hey, Tony, check left. Oh, geez, I'm in the shot again.
What happened, Fleets? You all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Oh, come here, quick, and give Helen a hand.
Oh, Daddy Longlegs.
You all right, Helen?
Yeah.
I gotta get myself an oxyacetylene torch.
You guys, I can't swim. I got tubes in my gills. Please.
Plenty of man. Let's get out of here.
Some of these guys look like milkmen, some like choreographers.
Trying to pack Mahler's 9th into the 30 seconds of music they got.
Well, I'm gonna go lodge a complaint with the commissioner of globe on a stick.
Oh, cripes, we wandered onto the set again. Let's swim.
Oh, yeah, see, that's what happens when you buy your creature restraints at Montgomery Wards.
Hey, Mom, look, the chain broke. Hey.
Hey, look, he broke the chain.
Thanks, Mike Wallace.
We're a pole vault here, and we should be...
Not the duck shoes.
Oops.
Well, this simplifies Helen's life.
Hey, hey, I got my bike receipt in my pocket. It's gonna get all wet.
Okay, pal, get this. This is my ool. Notice there's no pee in it? Let's try to keep it that way.
The woman in limbo is terrified.
Hey, can I get a towel here?
The world of turtle show will go on as scheduled.
Get out of my way, air sucker.
This is an emergency. The Gill Man has escaped. Please, please clear the ocean area. Get out, everybody.
Please don't panic, bud. The Gill Man has escaped. Oh, my God, we're all gonna die. We're all gonna die. Oh, oh, oh.
One in the Kingston trio.
You're on your own, honey.
The death of Cindy Brady.
The human mother distracts predators by laying on her young.
Taxi. Taxi, taxi, taxi, taxi.
Put him off. Put up your dukes. I'll fight you with both hands tied behind my back.
She's not really at the way he was at when he was snapping alligators.
All right, well, let me put her up here. Just look at your struts a little bit. Oh, gee.
Whoa, took out the cameraman.
Oh, hey, it's Bruce Dern in Coming Home.
You're out of touch, my baby.
Damn it, Jim, I'm a milkman, not a doctor.
He's gonna need a carbon blade to get those shorts off.
Oh, no, he's dead. It's so sad. It's just you and me, I guess. Oh, okay.
Well, so far, no downside.
I forgot my nose plugs.
Well, car overturn.
Extry, extry.
Tickets still available.
Gillman kills German tourists.
The incredible Mr. Limpet called in to help.
It is four days since the Gillman escaped.
Conflicting reports place the fearsome creature as far north as Norfolk, Virginia, and as far south as Panama.
Most experts believe the monster is either dead or on its way back to the Amazon.
Later, the Gillman meets up with Skipper and Gilligan.
Could someone lend me a Terry shirt jack, please?
Oh, the tepidity.
Come on, kids, break it up.
We weren't doing anything.
Well, that's good. It's time to go home. Come on, beat it.
Okay, officer, okay. Anything you say.
And Richard Speck's life changes forever.
The S.S. car pulling away.
Hold on, hold on. Can I get a ride to Long John Silver's?
Oh, rats it. Rats the way I like it. Rollie now. Rollie, ride him off.
Some dog's a Cure fan with all that black lipstick.
Oh, wow, this might be the coolest movie ever.
I award this movie ten stars.
Oh, good money.
Just ten volume tonight.
What a day. I fell for a daredevil. I barely got away.
Can we watch my life as a dog again tonight?
Oh, I see. It's like this, isn't it?
I mean, what is a taboo, really?
It's so hard to discuss our relationship when you won't stop licking yourself.
Hey, Chris sprung for a really nice candle tonight, huh?
Better lighten a few million more mosquitoes.
It's silly that I open the door for the creature every night.
He's not coming. Who am I kidding?
Okay, I think I'm over her.
Hey, Chihuahua.
Brah. Brah.
Now it's Sears' Jean Kirkpatrick lingerie.
Okay, she's nude right now.
Totally nude.
See?
Okay, I'll come in for a night tab.
Do I dare interrupt my smoking?
Well, I'm sure if it was a gill man in Helen's room, someone would let me know.
Back to hog futures.
Sit, stay. Good dog.
I'm gonna give that Chris a good piece of my mind.
Helen, are you all right?
Helen.
You know where the ice machine is?
Helen, did you kill a dog to lure me into your motel room?
I'm humectifying.
Who is it?
Spleat?
Well, I left him in the bedroom. Isn't he there?
No, I heard him howl.
Well, I'll be right with you.
I'll look for him outside.
I'll be reporting back on what I find outside. Thank you.
Chris?
Here, boy.
Here, Chris.
Here, Chris the dog.
Here, boy.
I wonder if there's a motel around here anywhere.
Here, Chris.
Christopher J. Dog, you get back here.
Wow.
Not as of yet.
My guess is that he slipped into another dimension.
I am? Oh.
We can take a leisurely cruise up the river and have dinner in Jacksonville.
My plane doesn't leave until midnight, so maybe we can go stepping for a couple of hours, if you like.
Oh, it sounds wonderful.
Will you miss me?
It'll be the longest three months.
Oh, the white-hot indifference.
If only he kissed me like Chris did.
Hey, your dog tasted terrible.
Chris!
It's Duluth, baby.
And now there'll be a scene with the creature and Cary Grant.
La cucaracha, la cucaracha.
With Mel Cooley on sax.
This is for a pal in Spandau. We love you, Rudolph.
Hogan.
Rock da Casbah, rock da Casbah.
It's hot. Let's go outside.
Alright.
That'll give the creature another opportunity to try for you and miss.
They have a wonderful five-meat buffet.
You know, this movie gives you a raw, unexplicated view of the life of a marine biologist.
Well, Prince Charming vanishes at midnight, and I won't see him for three long months.
Yeah. Oh, you mean me.
Maybe I can stretch a weekend.
Might as well be broke, that's the way I am.
So that's why you didn't pick up the check.
You know, scientists are funny.
Like Bill Nye.
Probe and measure and dissect.
With any luck.
Invent lights without heat.
Why, a caterpillar's eyebrow.
What?
But when it comes to really important things, we're as stupid as the cavemen.
Now hold on.
Like love.
Makes the world go round, but what do we know about it?
Is it a fact? Is it chemistry, electricity?
Can I touch your hinders, see if it does anything?
Once when I had a crush on the captain of the high school football team.
I looked it up in the dictionary.
And love, according to Mr. Webster, is a feeling of strong personal attachment induced by sympathetic understanding.
Have you ever heard such nonsense?
You want to get another Papa Burger?
I don't know.
Some things should remain unknown.
Cleat, party of five. Cleat.
I think a poet once said, "Randy, you're a fine girl."
Love is such a mystery. I cannot find it out.
But when I think I'm best resolved, I then am most in doubt.
Ah, Burma Shave.
Hey Cleat, we're doing the Macarena in here. Come on!
The film that drips with unabashed sensuality.
Oh really, I'm happy she's seeing other guys.
I've been dating a lamp, Ray, for a few weeks.
Hey, hey, you guys want to score me an order of fried clams?
I'd own some of those hush puppies. Don't skimp on the sauce.
I'll make her jealous. I'll go make out with the scrod.
Look, Cleat, you're a third wheel. Figure it out.
And then I spent a couple of years sorting socks, so that kept me busy for a while.
But other than that, I was just...
Hey, did you want to join us, Mark?
Hey, I didn't know we had an espresso machine.
Of course you didn't. You're new to the ship.
So Mike, how about letting me make you a lovely espresso or Frappuccino or something?
Yeah, sure, thanks. That'd be great.
So Mike, what brings you to the Satellite of Love?
Well, the subcraw I've been here for a while is at the edge of the universe,
and then I have it in my portfolio.
I bet it was hard to leave Illinois, Wisconsin.
I'm not from Elroy, so I've been grateful.
Oh, boy, that's something.
Say, Mike, I bet you like a nice, delicious chocolate shavings on your espresso, huh?
Sure, I sure would.
Hey, Mike, how do you and Chavo do each other?
Well, as I said, you know, we've been in this space for quite some time now.
It's so kind.
Everybody down.
He's got a laugh.
Oh, my God.
So, Mike, you were saying about that one, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's for sure.
Thank you.
Here you go, Mike.
A nice, delicious cup of latte espresso, Frappuccino, amaretto, whatever.
Okay.
Well, thanks. I hope you didn't go to any trouble.
No.
Oops, forgot your biscotti.
Oh, can't forget that.
It'll be just a second, Mark.
How is it?
It doesn't last long, but it's good.
I'll be right back.
Hogan, Hogan, Hogan.
Oscar Schindler and his big band.
Juicy got 'em crazy.
I could have brought my conch. I could have sat in.
Don't do that.
Shem Howard on the tenor sax.
Ah, geez, my tie is caught.
Oh, it hurts. Ow.
Hi, I'm evolving. Do you have a bathroom?
Let's show 'em how to jitterbug, baby.
And the John Birch Society meeting comes to an end.
I'll save you. I guess not.
Oh, okay.
Here, take a look at this dock piling, will ya?
You got my cake wet, you jerk.
I lost my tie tack.
They're splitting one beer?
Jane Wyman and Lee Harvey Oswald's first date.
Bob, the creature's rough-housing again.
Our salads are up.
That is the tiniest grilling rig I've ever seen.
Brings in a quart of oil every year.
What are you doing? You just put her up there.
McHale's Navy, knights.
McHale man kidnapped a woman from the lobster house at the foot of pier nine.
Pier nine, units one, seven, alerted to pier nine.
That's us.
That's so weird. I was wondering if it was us, and it was.
So that's what happened to Soyuz 7.
Helen!
Helen, are we seeing other people now?
Man in the water by the buoy.
Over here!
I need to pick up a take-out order at the lobster house.
I'm sure you're under arrest for trying to steal a buoy.
Sixty-seven. This is a sixty-seven.
Clear the streets of traffic. Order citizens indoors.
Police cars on detail nine one. We'll report to water front.
That's us.
Be on the lookout for Robert Bob Gillman, also known as the creature,
for mail fraud and bunco.
The Gillman is loose in Jacksonville.
Look out, ladies.
After kidnapping Miss Helen Dobson, a science student.
It is believed the monster may be on the prowl, ready to attack others.
The police have requested us to advise all citizens to remain indoors until further notice.
It is suggested that you keep all lights on,
as the creature seems not to be able to stand bright light.
Little late for exposition.
Leopold and Loeb, the high school years.
So I say to the old man, why should I stay in school?
You never finish, and you're doing okay.
You can't get a job without a college degree.
It's like my pop says it.
A college degree is like a high school diploma used to be.
He says, "Hey."
Did you happen to see?
What's that?
Looks like teen spirit.
Body's been washed ashore.
I think we better finish our sentences.
I'm just having so much fun with you tonight, Bryce.
He's out for a ride with his doppelganger.
Good thing they brought an aircraft landing light along.
Look at that. Is that Chantong?
Will you go out with me?
Wow, creature. Master of terrible timing.
Is she all right?
She's alive.
The creature's got a nice rising fast bow.
Please don't attach me to a block of tackle and throw me into a padded palm tree. No.
All right, I'll be back snapping alligators in two in no time.
Love, lift up, where I belong.
Where eagle fly.
Mountain high.
The report from Area 78 is incorrect.
Got it?
It is incorrect.
The gill man has not been sighted in that area.
We have an instant red herring.
He's headed for Brazil by now.
Yeah.
The bodies of two men have been found on the banks of the St. John's River.
Car 19 investigate bodies found near cars below Pointe Diego.
Could be him. Let's go.
Here is a partial list of other places where the gill man has not been sighted.
Bangor, Maine. Jackson Hole, Wyoming.
The Quad Cities.
Brainerd, Minnesota.
Well, you were a bitch to my parents this evening.
Look what we found, a sand dollar.
Last one in is a rotten egg.
Yeah, looks like someone attached him to a rope and swung him into a tree.
Get a load of that.
There's another one over there.
I suppose they got to fill out a report or something.
Look, there's another one over there.
A moose, let's follow him.
All emergency equipment is being mobilized at Pointe Diego,
where the bodies of two students, victims of the gill man, were found.
So far there's been no trace of Miss Helen Dobson, the pretty young scientist,
kidnapped by the monster.
Her fiancé, Professor Clete Ferguson, is aiding in the search.
Clete.
The police department asked me to repeat this message.
Five, four, three, two, one.
You're on the air.
Pointe Diego.
Give me your attention.
I want you to comb this beach and surrounding area carefully.
But under no circumstances are any of you to investigate shrubbery hoats
or other possible places of concealment.
Shrubbery hoats?
Unless you are accompanied by an armed guard.
I smell bacon.
Now the trucks will disperse in both directions and unload about a thousand yards apart.
Now you've met all our flashlights.
We do?
I want you to check them right now to see whether they're in order or not.
All right, come on.
Turn them on.
Now shake them and it'll look like I'm in an old-fashioned movie.
Good.
Now if any of you spot the gill man, report to your group leader.
He'll fire his very pistol and the professor now will get there as soon as possible.
Very pistol.
May I say something to the man captain?
No.
Professor Ferguson would like to say something to you.
Money.
Everybody needs it.
I want to impress upon you once again something the captain said before.
Don't take any chances.
Go to the bathroom before we leave.
This is a thinking creature we're hunting.
Wildly, cruel, dangerous.
As strong as any ten of you.
Two men have already lost their lives tonight.
Who's next?
A girl is missing.
I want to find that girl alive more than anything else in the world.
You have no idea.
But I don't want a single one of you men to risk your life needlessly.
Remember that this creature can't stay out of water for more than a few minutes.
That limits our search to a narrow strip along the river.
So please, obey the captain's instructions to the letter.
Shouldn't we get going?
Then why would you spot the gill man reported to your group leader?
And he'll fire his very pistol.
I'm going to bring up your next scientist now.
He's a...
That's it men. Get at it.
Scatter aimlessly everyone.
Go.
Okay, which strip club are we meeting at?
And they immediately forget their instructions.
Yeah, we got to get these spotlights back to A and Z party rental.
Oh, I thought the plug took her down.
You know he's not that bad looking.
Just a toupee and a little something to take the shine off his nose.
Sure.
Honey, we always do the same thing when we go out.
You put me on the ground unconscious and go off and kill.
So you don't like bottom feeders, right?
So no carp.
Bullheads.
Okay.
That's the easiest part of the Engos channel to cross.
The fallen rise of reginald creature.
The first mobile used car lot.
Good thing they enlisted the help of the joads.
Oh man, I just stepped into the tub.
Honey, all I can find are crappies. Is that okay?
Where did you drop your glasses, Earl?
Hey, there's a nightcrawler.
Joe, turn that light back. I think I saw something.
Anything to make you happy, man.
Just for tonight, can we get along?
Hold it.
I knew I saw something.
I can't make it out, but that's no kill man, bub.
Name's Joe, Mac.
That's not driftwood either, buster.
Name's Max, sport.
Any of you guys want to go with me?
Sorry, we have book club.
Keep us lamp right where it is.
Right.
If you find anything, make with the high side.
Yeah.
How about a nice turtle?
Don't cry for me, Argentina.
Mac, bub, pal, guys, sporto, come on.
Holy cow.
Cubs win, cubs win.
Throw the flashlights at him, boys.
And go.
The fleek couldn't get through there, professor.
Jay Buhner just hit a homer.
Let's move, boys.
To the strip clubs, gentlemen.
Get the scooch over, Terry.
Thrill to the moderate pace of the chase.
Tremble as they carefully set their trip odometer.
Oh, he's got black badge.
Oh, look.
I'm just out for a walk. This is so racist.
Creech, honey, it's just the neighbors.
Come on back to bed, sweetie.
Look, I am doing it.
Oh, he's leaking.
Remember your instructions.
The professor is at command from now on.
You take orders from him.
The ichthyology department at the State U
has declared martial law.
Well, there really wasn't much we could have done.
They told us not to endanger ourselves unnecessarily and all.
We're going for munchies. You want anything?
There he goes.
Our flashlights are working.
Fire!
Stop!
Nah, get bent.
Come on, please.
Um, Haltensee.
What's fish for stop?
We'll offer you Marge Shot if you stop.
Wait a minute. Who, me or her?
Wait, are you talking to her?
You should have thought of this three movies ago.
You know what? Well, not really figuring in the final scene.
I'm glad they checked their flashlights anyway.
I was gonna break up with her anyway.
The disorganized, short-lived, badly botched,
and thoroughly ineffectual revenge of the creature.
He's not so much a hero as a very effective administrator.
What if he never relinquishes control of the police department?
Well...
And for the final indignity, he lands on a puffer fish.
Why the hell did I stop?
Oh...
Finally, some respite from the breakneck roller coaster piece that was this movie.
Whoo! Man.
The creature's name was Lou Gibson?
That wasn't very clear in the movie.
That poor, slimy creature in love with that beautiful woman.
Yeah, I feel bad for the Gill Man, too.
Whoo!
Ha ha ha.
Hi, everyone. Kind of a tough moment.
We just tapped into Earth genealogy records
and discovered the cause of the Simeon Holocaust.
You see, virtually every single one of Mike's descendants married apes.
Come on, all my grandkids?
Uh, yep. What about great-grandchildren?
Checking...yes.
Frances Nelson married a macaque.
Otherwise, they all married great apes.
You can see why he's kind of upset, folks.
Thomas Ryan Nelson married a slow loris.
We have an R.W. Nelson, probably great-great-grandchild,
who married a roughed lemur.
Yep, your family liked its monkeys, Mike.
Still, I imagine by then, though, it wasn't that unusual.
Oh, it was quite unusual.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Here's our Wilbert H. Nelson, who married a Sarah Thompson
from Oak Park, Illinois.
Oh, that's good.
Oh, seems he kept an eye-eye in an apartment downtown.
This is not pretty stuff.
Here's a W.D. Nelson, was married eight times,
silverback gorilla one through three.
Then he picked up a pension for the bonobo
and married those four times before wedding an Japanese snow monkey
on his 84th birthday.
Okay, okay, thanks, Carl. I think everyone's heard enough.
I think we all get the point.
Mike, I think I speak for all of us when I say,
"Good one, Nelson."
I'm locking up my sock monkey. I'll give you that much for free.
That's me personally.
I don't know how you rate bright eyes,
but the lawgiver is coming to see you, so shape up.
Let's look alive, people. Give up that fire swing.
Lawgiver, we're delighted that you could make it.
Get your stinking paws off me, you damn dirty ape.
Nelson, we meet again.
Mrs. Forrester?
You, the lawgiver, but how?
Here's the short story.
You see, after my... spread out.
You see, after my beloved Clayton turned into a star baby,
I vowed... get off!
I vowed to do it differently.
I vowed to raise him to be as fine a young man
as you could ever, ever hope to see.
But I got busy and I never got around to it,
so I got another hopeless idiot
who started off on his mad experiment.
And then it happened.
My beloved Clayton passed away.
When I was done smothering him, I vowed to avenge his death.
He asked me on his death bed to keep the experiment going,
no matter what the cost.
This is the short story, right?
So when I died, I asked someone to freeze my body,
which they did, and it was really quite reasonable.
Five hundred years later, the apes thawed me out,
cured my freezer burn, and that's why I'm the lawgiver.
Well, I can see that certainly makes a lot of... huh?
And I will keep my word, Melstone.
I will avenge my son's death.
I will dog you to the end of the universe!
[laughing]
Banana lawgiver?
Hey, I'm laughing here.
[laughing]
[music]